

Aravind Kumar Mullapudi

Data Engineer

A tech-savvy, meticulous, and competent IT professional with over 3 years of pioneering experience in Data Engineering, SQL Server Database Administration, MSBI (SSRS, SSIS, SQL), and Power BI with special emphasis on development, analysis, and testing. Seeking to prove and utilize my skills effectively and efficiently to provide impetus to my career in the process of achieving organizational goals in Data Engineering.

xaravindmullapudi@gmail.com



Wakefield, United Kingdom

+91 7898641546



in linkedin.com/in/aravind-kumar-6a6155117

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Engineer

Pinion Services Limited

05/2018 - Present, Wakefield, United Kingdom Growth Path: Database Administrator (May 2018 - Feb 2020) | Data Engineer (Feb 2020 - Present)

- Work as Data Engineer and provide Data Engineering expertise to create state-of-the-art data-driven solutions by utilizing tools & technologies that ensure the attainment of client business goals.
- Ingested data from different data sources using various technologies/languages like SQL, Python and REST API. Communicated with the data architects on the dataflow design and suggested changes that can improve performance.
- Came up with idea to overcome the informatica CT capturing issue. Communicated with the database administration team on optimizing the runtimes of the ETL loads by implementing indexes and partitioning of the large tables.
- Provide leadership with a vision that assists in the creation and promotion of an environment for innovation, organizational agility, and continuous learning. Built a ETL pipelines in informatica that load data from various sources to DWH staging layer with SCD1, SCD2 model. Writing as complex SQL stored procedure to manipulate and load data as per BU request.
- Provide full lifecycle support to clients for database administration from initial client interaction and requirements analysis through design, coding, testing, debugging, implementation and integration.
- Implement Database features like DB Chaining, partitioning, Change Tracking, and CDC in both SQL and Oracle database servers. Monitor SQL Server jobs like backup, database space, log space, stored procedures, SSIS Packages, etc.
- Streamline database design and implementation tasks including design database naming convention and physical storage configuration, database export & import, data migration/ conversion, and transition.
- troubleshooting, resolve data integrity performance issues. Use SQL Profiler, query execution plans, trace flags, and Perfmon to aid in troubleshooting. Create and deploy the servers and data in Microsoft Azure. Manage the users in the Azure active directory portal. Planning for migration from SQL server to Snowflake Datawarehouse.
- Design and implement the Power BI dashboards for reporting the critical financial systems. Partner with project teams on the development of Power BI reports.
- Work with other members of the data management team, infrastructure team, development team and other groups to build and support high availability database instances and processes. Develop and adhere to database standards and procedures. Maintain documentation related to database platforms, guidelines, methods, and standards.

SKILLS

Data Warehousing Data Engineering

Business Intelligence Database Management

SQL Server Database Application Design and

Administration Development

Requirement Elicitation **Data Migration**

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Scripting Language:

SQL, PL-SQL and Python

Reporting Tool:

Power BI. SSRS

Databases:

SQL Server 2005-19, Oracle 10g and Microsoft Azure SQL database

ETL Tools:

SSIS, Informatica(IICS)

EDUCATION

Master's MSc Advanced Computing

University of Huddersfield - Huddersfield, UK

Bachelor's Information Technology

SRM University - Chennai, India

CERTIFICATES

Certified with SNOW PRO

Certified with DP-900 Azure Data Fundamentals

Certification of DP-203 in progress

ACHIEVEMENTS

Drove unprecedented results by reducing 17 hours of manual work through designing the reports that eliminate manual monitoring.

Eliminated the manual work of code deployments by taking initiative and creating DevOps pipelines which save 30hours

PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

Impeccable Analytical skills

Eloquent

Ethical